Inventory of the Howard A. Reed papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- National Education of Turkey consultant file, 1983-1999 (Folder 99-113)
  - Printed matter on Turkish economy and education, 1992-1996 (Folder 113)
- International College file (Folder 113)
  - History of International College, Beirut, 1990 (Folder 113)
  - International College Newsletter, 1994-1995 (Folder 113)
  - Yearbook, 1999 (Folder 114: 1)
  - Planner, 1991 (Folder 114: 2)
  - Catalog, photocopy, 1931 (Folder 114: 3)
  - Newsletters and research materials, 1998-1999 (Folder 114: 4-6)
  - Senior class song by Caleb Lawrence, 1932 (Folder 114: 7)
    Includes photocopies of photographs
  - "Zionists,", 1993-1996 (Folder 114: 8)
    Includes copies of articles and clippings
- Printed matter (Folder 114-115)
  - Association of Turkish American Scientists (ATAS) conference proceedings, 1995 (Folder 114: 9)
  - Brookings Institution Media Guide, 1998-1999 (Folder 114: 10)
  - Cumulative Index to the Middle East Journal, 1967-1977 (Folder 115: 1)
  - Center for Middle East Studies, Harvard University, 1985 (Folder 115: 2)
  - Clippings on Turkey, 1994; 2000 (Folder 115: 3)
- Mardin, Şerif. "Religion and Social Change: The Case of Bediuzzaman Said Nursi,", undated (Folder 115: 4)
- McCarty, Justin. "Muslims and Minorities: The Population of Ottoman Anatolia and the End of the Empire,", 1983 (Folder 115: 5)
- Abu-Ghazaleh, Adnan. "American Missions and Arab Nationalism in 19th Century Syria,", undated (Folder 115: 6)
- Turkey printed matter, 1990-1994 (Folder 115: 7-8)
- Photocopy of encyclopedia article on Turkey, undated (Folder 115: 9)
  In Turkish
- University of Connecticut History Department newsletter, 1997 (Folder 115: 10)
  Includes related correspondence
- Reed family genealogy, 1984 (Folder 115: 11)
- Newsletters, 1993-1994 (Folder 115: 12)
- Turkey (Folder 115-116)
  - Tourism, 1998-1999 (Folder 115: 13-14)
  - Seminar notes, 1994 (Folder 115: 15)
  - Economy and commerce, 1984-1993 (Folder 116: 1-2)
  - Islam, 1990-1994 (Folder 116: 3)
  - Education, 1991-1999 (Folder 116: 4-6)
    Includes Türk eğitiminde konular ve imkânlar by Howard A. Reed, 1991
- Middle East Studies Association file. "Turkish Universities in Rapid Flux-Challenges and Responses," conference session proposals, 1994 (Folder 116: 7-8)
- Miscellany, 1986; undated (Folder 116: 9)
- International College file (Folder 117-119)
  - Research materials on International College of Beirut and American University of Beirut, including history, 1957-1995 (Folder 117: 1-4)
  - International College of Smyrna [Izmir] photographs, postcards, and ephemera, 1914-1920 (Folder 117: 5)
    Includes negatives
  - Correspondence of Howard A. Reed, F. H. Bacon (uncle), and Cass Arthur Reed (father), 1936-1937 (Folder 117: 6)
    Includes photographs
  - Board of Trustees of International College of Smyrna [Izmir] meeting minutes. (Folder 118)
    Copies from microfilm
    - Volume III, 1909-1934 (Folder 118: 1)
    - Volume IV, 1935 January-1949 April (Folder 118: 2)
    - Volume V, 1949 April-1958 March (Folder 118: 3)
  - Board of Trustees of International College of Beirut meeting minutes (Folder 118)
    - 1960 November-1961 December (Folder 118: 4)
    - 1962 January-1962 November (Folder 118: 5)
    - 1970 April-1971 April (Folder 118: 6)
  - Near East College Association, Inc. meeting minutes (Folder 119)
    - 1927 March-1951 December (Folder 119: 1)
    - 1952 February-1961 June (Folder 119: 2)
  - American University of Beirut notes, 1995 (Folder 119: 3)
  - History of International College by Bayard Dodge, 1968 (Folder 119: 4)
  - American University of Beirut/International College correspondence and notes regarding cooperation between institutions, 1960-1984 (Folder 119: 5-6)